Guide to the Whitman College Delta Gamma records 1903-2016
Whitman College and Northwest Archives
Whitman College Delta Gamma records
1903-2016
Whitman College and Northwest Archives 345 Boyer Avenue Walla Walla, WA 99362 Archives@whitman.edu https://library.whitman.edu/archives/
Delta Gamma. Alpha Eta Chapter
WCA053
2.5 linear feet 4 boxes
The Alpha Eta chapter of the Delta Gamma national sorority was established at Whitman in 1916. This collection consists of memoranda, news articles, photographs, memorabilia, scrapbooks, and other records related to the sorority.
Collection is open for research.
Delta Gamma was established in 1873 at the Lewis School for Girls in Oxford, Mississippi. The Whitman College Chapter of the sorority, Alpha Eta, was chartered in 1916 from local sorority, Gamma Kappa, which holds the distinction of being the first known unofficial fraternal association on campus, as it was likely established in 1903. The sorority, sometimes refered to as D.G., is the longest continually operating sorority on campus.
This collection consists of memoranda, news articles, photographs, memorabilia, scrapbooks, and other records related to the Whitman College chapter of Delta Gamma.
Whitman College--History; Greek letter societies
Colleges and Universities
- "The Anchora of Delta Gamma", 1916-1971 (Box 1, Folder 1-98)
- Anniversaries and Alumni, 1950-1982 (Box 2, Folder 1)
- Correspondence, 1967-1985 (Box 2, Folder 2)
- Gamma Kappa: Membership book, 1903-1916 (Box 2, Folder 3)
- Luncheon in honor of the Cordiners, 1968 (Box 2, Folder 4)
- Membership lists, 1912-1914 (Box 2, Folder 5)
- Nancy Ann Evans class of 1954, photographs and clippings, 1973 (Box 2, Folder 6)
- Newspaper articles, 1931-1981 (Box 2, Folder 7)
- Dance and event programs, 1921-1959 (Box 3, Folder 1-6)
- Philanthropic efforts, 1961-1997 (Box 2, Folder 8)
- Photographs, 1926-1996 (Box 2, Folder 9-15)
- Reading list, undated (Box 2, Folder 16)
- Social events and invitations, 1922-2016 (Box 2, Folder 17)
- Study tables, 1993-1995 (Box 2, Folder 18)
- Scrapbook: Peggy Woodward, circa 1930 (Box 4, Object 1)